{"name": "B02 2019-6", "questions": [{"title": "", "name": "", "article": "<p><br/></p>", "question": "1. A calculator has a regular price of $59.95 before taxes. It goes on sale at 20% below the regular price. Before taxes are added, what is the sale price of the calculator?", "choices": {"A": "$11.99", "B": "$29.98", "C": "$39.95", "D": "$47.96", "E": "$54.95"}, "correct": "D"}, {"title": "", "name": "", "article": "", "question": "2. Given r = 6, b = 4, and g = -9,  (r + b - g)(b + g) = ?", "choices": {"A": " -95", "B": "-5", "C": "5", "D": "13", "E": " 14"}, "correct": "A"}, {"title": "", "name": "", "article": "", "question": "3. In the figure below, C is on BD , \u2220BAC measures 42\u00b0, and \u2220ABC measures 108\u00b0. What is the measure of \u2220ACD? ", "choices": {"A": "108\u00b0", "B": "120\u00b0", "C": "132\u00b0", "D": "138\u00b0", "E": "150\u00b0"}, "correct": "E"}, {"title": "", "name": "", "article": "", "question": "4. If , then  ?", "choices": {"A": "", "B": " ", "C": " ", "D": "", "E": "45"}, "correct": "C"}, {"title": "", "name": "", "article": "", "question": "5. What is the length, in inches, of the hypotenuse of a right triangle with a leg that is 9 inches long and a leg that is 2 inches long?", "choices": {"A": "", "B": " ", "C": " ", "D": "5.5", "E": "11"}, "correct": "C"}, {"title": "", "name": "", "article": "", "question": "6. A bag contains exactly 18 solid-colored buttons: 3 red, 5 blue, and 10 white. What is the probability of randomly selecting 1 button that is NOT white?", "choices": {"A": "", "B": " ", "C": "", "D": " ", "E": " "}, "correct": "C"}, {"title": "", "name": "", "article": "", "question": "7. What is the sum of 3 consecutive odd integers whose mean is 27?", "choices": {"A": "39", "B": "75", "C": "81", "D": "87", "E": "93"}, "correct": "C"}, {"title": "", "name": "", "article": "", "question": "8. Two dials are shown below. When the arrow on each dial is spun, it is equally likely to point at any of the numbered sectors on its dial after it has stopped spinning. After the arrows are next spun, the numbers in the sectors the arrows point at after they stop spinning will be added together. Which of the following values is NOT a possible sum of those 2 numbers? ", "choices": {"A": "1", "B": "4", "C": "6", "D": "7", "E": "8"}, "correct": "E"}, {"title": "", "name": "", "article": "", "question": "9. On a bike trail there are 5 checkpoints numbered in order, Checkpoint 1 through Checkpoint 5, as shown in the figure below. Some distances along the trail between 2 checkpoints are given: 6.6 miles between 1 and 3; 4.5 miles between 2 and 3; and 9.7 miles between 2 and 5. Which of the following values is closest to the distance, in miles, along the trail between Checkpoint 1 and Checkpoint 5? ", "choices": {"A": "11.1", "B": "11.8", "C": "14.2", "D": "16.3", "E": "20.8"}, "correct": "B"}, {"title": "", "name": "", "article": "", "question": "10. In the figure below, a circle with a radius of 10 meters circumscribes a regular hexagon. What is the perimeter, in meters, of the hexagon?", "choices": {"A": "30", "B": "", "C": "60", "D": "", "E": ""}, "correct": "C"}, {"title": "", "name": "", "article": "", "question": "11. To produce aluminum softball bats, it costs the Recreation Equipment Supply Company $3, 500 for overhead, plus $2 per softball bat produced, What is the maximum number of bats that can be produced by the company for $15,000?", "choices": {"A": "1,750", "B": "3,502", "C": "5,000", "D": "5,750", "E": "7,500"}, "correct": "D"}, {"title": "", "name": "", "article": "", "question": "12. Given that 3x+2=4 and 2y+6=5, what is x+y?", "choices": {"A": "", "B": "", "C": "", "D": "", "E": " "}, "correct": "B"}, {"title": "", "name": "", "article": "", "question": "13. For all  such that , which of the following expressions is equivalent to  ?", "choices": {"A": "8x", "B": "28x", "C": "3x+5", "D": "3x\u00b2+5", "E": "15x\u00b2+5"}, "correct": "C"}, {"title": "", "name": "", "article": "", "question": "14. What is the value of the expression \uff1f", "choices": {"A": "-8", "B": "", "C": "", "D": "", "E": "8"}, "correct": "E"}, {"title": "", "name": "", "article": "", "question": "15. Karen invested $2,000 in a special sayings account. The balance of this special savings account will double every 5 years. Assuming that Karen makes no other deposits and no withdrawals, what will be the balance of Karen's investment at the end of 40 years?", "choices": {"A": "$80,000", "B": "$256,000", "C": "$400,000", "D": "$512,000", "E": "$1,024,000"}, "correct": "D"}, {"title": "", "name": "", "article": "", "question": "16. The graph below shows the amount of water in a pond over a period of 7 hours. One of the following values is the number of hours the amount of water in the pond remained constant. Which one\uff1f", "choices": {"A": "2", "B": "3", "C": "3.5", "D": "4", "E": "7"}, "correct": "A"}, {"title": "", "name": "", "article": "", "question": "17. If it rains in Franklin City on a particular day, the probability that it will rain there the following day is 0.70. If it does not rain in Franklin City on a particular day, the probability that it will rain there the following day is 0.10. Given that it rained in Franklin City on Monday, what is the probability that it will NOT rain in Franklin City on Tuesday of the same week?", "choices": {"A": "0.10", "B": "0.30", "C": "0.60", "D": "0.70", "E": "0.90"}, "correct": "B"}, {"title": "", "name": "", "article": "", "question": "18. In the standard (x, y) coordinate plane, what is the slope of the line given by the equation 5x=9y+18?", "choices": {"A": "", "B": "", "C": "", "D": "5", "E": "9"}, "correct": "B"}, {"title": "", "name": "", "article": "", "question": "19. One of the following equations represents the line graphed in the standard (x, y)coordinate plane below. Which one?", "choices": {"A": "y=-2x+2", "B": "y=-2x+4", "C": "y=2x+4", "D": "y=4x-2", "E": "y=4x+2"}, "correct": "B"}, {"title": "", "name": "", "article": "", "question": "20. In the figure below, line m is perpendicular to line n, and line p is parallel to line q. Lines m, n, and p intersect at a single point. Some angle measures are given. What is the value of x?", "choices": {"A": "32", "B": "58", "C": "122", "D": "148", "E": "158"}, "correct": "D"}, {"title": "", "name": "", "article": "", "question": "21. A bag contains 10 solid-colored marbles of the same size: 3 red, 2 green, yellow, and 4 blue. Which of the following expressions gives the probability of drawing, at random and without replacement, a blue marble on the 1st draw, a green marble on the 2nd draw, and a blue marble on the 3rd draw?", "choices": {"A": "", "B": "", "C": "", "D": "", "E": ""}, "correct": "D"}, {"title": "", "name": "", "article": "", "question": "22. A physical education teacher recorded the distances, in inches, that her students jumped during a long jump lesson. The distances of 1 jump by each of the students are represented in the stem-and-leaf plot below.What is the probability that a student chosen at random from the class will have jumped at least 60 inches?", "choices": {"A": "", "B": "", "C": "", "D": "", "E": ""}, "correct": "E"}, {"title": "", "name": "", "article": "", "question": "23. Given that the function f defined as f(x)=5-3x has domain (-1, 0, 2), what is the range of f ?", "choices": {"A": "{-2,0,4}", "B": "{-1,2,8}", "C": "{-1,5,8}", "D": "{2,5,8}", "E": "{2,5,11}"}, "correct": "C"}, {"title": "", "name": "", "article": "", "question": "24. To the nearest 1 foot, what is the height of a rectangular prism with a base length of 15 feet, a base width of  feet, and a volume of 100 cubic feet?", "choices": {"A": "5", "B": "7", "C": "9", "D": "20", "E": "75"}, "correct": "A"}, {"title": "", "name": "", "article": "", "question": "25. Tables of values for the 2 functions  and  are shown below. What is the value of ?", "choices": {"A": "-21", "B": "-7", "C": "-5", "D": "3", "E": "9"}, "correct": "C"}, {"title": "", "name": "", "article": "", "question": "26. In the figure shown below, a ladder 15 feet long forms an angle of 56\u00b0 with the level ground as it leans against the vertical side of a building. The distance along the building, in feet, between the ground and the top of the ladder is equal to which of the following expressions?", "choices": {"A": "", "B": "", "C": "15 sin 56\u00b0", "D": "15 cos 56\u00b0", "E": "15 tan 56\u00b0"}, "correct": "C"}, {"title": "", "name": "", "article": "", "question": "27. The isotope iodine-131 has a half-life of 8 days, which means that the amount of iodine-131 remaining after t days is , where N is the number of grams of iodine-131 at t=0. How many grams of iodine-131 will remain after 16 days if there were 32 grams of iodine-131 at t=0?", "choices": {"A": "0", "B": "2", "C": "8", "D": "16", "E": "128"}, "correct": "C"}, {"title": "", "name": "", "article": "", "question": "28. Which of the following expressions is equivalent to  ?", "choices": {"A": "", "B": "", "C": "", "D": "", "E": ""}, "correct": "A"}, {"title": "", "name": "", "article": "", "question": "29. Two concentric circles have radii of 5 centimeters and 6 centimeters, respectively. How many centimeters longer is the circumference of the larger circle than that of the smaller circle?", "choices": {"A": "1", "B": "\u03c0", "C": "2\u03c0", "D": "11\u03c0", "E": "22\u03c0"}, "correct": "C"}, {"title": "", "name": "", "article": "", "question": "30. Squares with sides of length x cm have been removed from each corner of a rectangle measuring 8 cm by 18 cm, resulting in the figure shown below. In terms of x, what is the area, in square centimeters, of the figure?", "choices": {"A": "", "B": "", "C": "", "D": "", "E": ""}, "correct": "B"}, {"title": "", "name": "", "article": "", "question": "31. In the standard (x,y) coordinate plane below, \u25b3ABC will be translated 10 units down and then the resulting, image will be reflected over the y-axis. What will be the coordinates of the final image of A resulting from both transformations?", "choices": {"A": "(-5,9)", "B": "(-1,9)", "C": "(1,-9)", "D": "(5,-10)", "E": "(5,-9)"}, "correct": "E"}, {"title": "", "name": "", "article": "", "question": "32. Olivia, Ashton, and Jane are standing on a soccer field such that Olivia is 20 meters due west of Ashton and Jane is 40 meters due north of Ashton. Their positions are at the vertices of a triangle. Which of the following expressions gives the degree measure of the angle of the triangle at the vertex where Olivia is standing?", "choices": {"A": "", "B": "", "C": "", "D": "", "E": ""}, "correct": "D"}, {"title": "", "name": "", "article": "<p><br/></p>", "question": "33. Use the following information to answer questions 33-35.In the standard (x,y) coordinate plane below, \u25b3AOB is formed by , the x-axis, and the y-axis.33. What is the area of \u25b3AOB in square coordinate units?", "choices": {"A": "6", "B": "", "C": "12", "D": "18", "E": "36"}, "correct": "D"}, {"title": "", "name": "", "article": "<p><br/></p>", "question": "34. Use the following information to answer questions 33-35.In the standard (x,y) coordinate plane below, \u25b3AOB is formed by , the x-axis, and the y-axis.34. What is the length of AB in coordinate units?", "choices": {"A": "", "B": "", "C": "", "D": "6", "E": "12"}, "correct": "B"}, {"title": "", "name": "", "article": "<p><br/></p>", "question": "35. Use the following information to answer questions 33-35.In the standard (x,y) coordinate plane below, \u25b3AOB is formed by , the x-axis, and the y-axis.35. Which of the following is an equation of ?", "choices": {"A": "y=-x+6", "B": "y=x-6", "C": "y=x+6", "D": "y=-6x-6", "E": "y=6x+6"}, "correct": "A"}, {"title": "", "name": "", "article": "", "question": "36. Which of the following arranges the numbers , 1.8, 1.08, and 1.08 into ascending order? (Note: The overbar notation shows that the digits under the bar will repeat. For example, 1.73 = 1.737373 ... )", "choices": {"A": "\uff1c 1.08 \uff1c 1.08 \uff1c 1.8", "B": "&lt; 1.08 &lt; 1.08 &lt; 1.8", "C": "1.08 &lt; 1.08 &lt;&lt; 1.8", "D": "1.08 &lt; 1.08 &lt; 1.8 &lt;", "E": "1.08 &lt; 1.08 &lt;&lt; 1.8 "}, "correct": "E"}, {"title": "", "name": "", "article": "", "question": "37. Andre's Floral Shop asked each of 20 customers to give a rating of the shop's service. The table below summarizes the 20 customer ratings.Which of the following values is closest to the mean of the 20 customer ratings?", "choices": {"A": "1.8", "B": "2.0", "C": "2.3", "D": "2.7", "E": "3.3"}, "correct": "A"}, {"title": "", "name": "", "article": "", "question": "38. Which of the following operations will produce the largest result when substituted for the blank in the expression 14___?", "choices": {"A": " Plus", "B": " Minus", "C": " Divides by", "D": " Multiplied by", "E": "Averaged with"}, "correct": "B"}, {"title": "", "name": "", "article": "", "question": "39. A local bowling league established its handicap for bowlers who have an average of 200 or less as 75% of the difference between 200 and the bowler's average score. If H represents the handicap of such a bowler and A represents his or her average score, which of the following equations gives H in terms of A ?", "choices": {"A": " ", "B": "", "C": "", "D": " ", "E": ""}, "correct": "E"}, {"title": "", "name": "", "article": "", "question": "40. The equation t = -0.0066a + 15 models the noon temperature, t degrees Celsius, a meters above sea level, on a certain day on Laurel Mountain. According to this equation, what would be the noon temperature for that certain day on Laurel Mountain at sea level?", "choices": {"A": "0\u00b0C", "B": "0.0066\u00b0C", "C": "14.9934\u00b0C", "D": "15\u00b0C", "E": "15.0066\u00b0C"}, "correct": "D"}, {"title": "", "name": "", "article": "", "question": "41. The semicircular top surface of Ron's patio is shown below. Which of the following values is closest to the area, in square feet, of the top surface of the patio?", "choices": {"A": "18", "B": "36", "C": "54", "D": "108", "E": "186"}, "correct": "C"}, {"title": "", "name": "", "article": "", "question": "42. Which of the following equations is that of a circle that is in the standard (x,y) coordinate plane, has center (1,-4), and has a radius of 5 coordinate units?", "choices": {"A": "", "B": "", "C": "", "D": "", "E": ""}, "correct": "D"}, {"title": "", "name": "", "article": "", "question": "43. What is the smallest positive integer having exactly 5 different positive integer divisors?", "choices": {"A": "5", "B": "6", "C": "12", "D": "16", "E": "18"}, "correct": "D"}, {"title": "", "name": "", "article": "", "question": "44. If  and , then ?", "choices": {"A": "", "B": "", "C": "", "D": "3", "E": ""}, "correct": "E"}, {"title": "", "name": "", "article": "", "question": "45. Florencia has 60 feet of fencing and a 4-foot-wide gate to use to enclose a dog pen. Among the following, a dog pen of which shape and dimensions will have the largest area if only the fencing and the gate are used to enclose it?", "choices": {"A": "A square with a side length of 16 feet", "B": "A square with a side length of 17 feet", "C": "A rectangle with a length of 14 feet and a width of 16 feet", "D": "A rectangle with a length of 15 feet and a width of 17 feet", "E": "A rectangle with a length of 15 feet and a width of 18 feet"}, "correct": "A"}, {"title": "", "name": "", "article": "", "question": "46. The difference  lies in which of the following intervals graphed on the real number line?", "choices": {"A": "", "B": " ", "C": " ", "D": "", "E": " "}, "correct": "D"}, {"title": "", "name": "", "article": "", "question": "47. The recursive formula for a sequence is given below, where  is the value of the nth term. Which of the following equations is an explicit formula for this sequence?", "choices": {"A": "", "B": "", "C": "", "D": "", "E": ""}, "correct": "B"}, {"title": "", "name": "", "article": "", "question": "48. The probabilities that each of 2 independent events will occur are given in the table below.What is the probability that both Events A and B will occur\u2014that is, P(A and B) ?", "choices": {"A": "0.08", "B": "0.20", "C": "0.30", "D": "0.50", "E": "0.60"}, "correct": "A"}, {"title": "", "name": "", "article": "", "question": "49. What is the solution set of the equation  ?", "choices": {"A": "{-25,4}", "B": "{-25,-2,2}", "C": "{-5,-4,5}", "D": "{-5, 5,-2i,2i}", "E": "{-2, 2,-5i,5i}"}, "correct": "E"}, {"title": "", "name": "", "article": "", "question": "50. Use the following information to answer questions 50-52.Skyline Tours is offering hot-air-balloon tours. The tables below give information about the balloon, the equipment, and the tours offered.50. Jarrod is looking up at a hot-air balloon. The balloon is currently at the maximum altitude during Tour C. The angle of elevation from the horizon is 37\u00b0, as shown in the figure below. Which of the following expressions is closest to the distance, d feet, from Jarrod to the basket?", "choices": {"A": "", "B": "", "C": "1,000 sin 37\u00b0", "D": "1,000 cos 37\u00b0", "E": "1,000 tan 37\u00b0"}, "correct": "A"}, {"title": "", "name": "", "article": "", "question": "51. Use the following information to answer questions 50-52.Skyline Tours is offering hot-air-balloon tours. The tables below give information about the balloon, the equipment, and the tours offered.51. Skyline Tours made $5,000 in 1 day by selling a total of 30 tickets for Tours A, B, and C. They sold twice as many tickets for Tour B as for Tour A. How many tickets were sold for Tour C ?", "choices": {"A": "4", "B": "8", "C": "12", "D": "16", "E": "18"}, "correct": "E"}, {"title": "", "name": "", "article": "", "question": "52. Use the following information to answer questions 50-52.Skyline Tours is offering hot-air-balloon tours. The tables below give information about the balloon, the equipment, and the tours offered.52. Jarrod went on Tour A, and his trip covered a distance of 6 miles. Bhumi went on Tour C, and her trip covered a distance of 9 miles. Which of the following values is the difference, in miles per hour, of the average speeds of their balloons during their tours?", "choices": {"A": "0", "B": "2", "C": " 3", "D": " 8", "E": " 9"}, "correct": "B"}, {"title": "", "name": "", "article": "", "question": "53. A forest fire is contained within a triangular region, which is shown below. The supervising firefighter plans to fight the fire by positioning a firefighter about every 4 meters along the perimeter of the triangle. Among the following, which expression best estimates the planned number of firefighters along the perimeter?  (Note: The law of sines states that in every triangle, the 3 ratios of length of a side to the sine of the angle opposite that side are equal.)", "choices": {"A": "", "B": "", "C": "", "D": "", "E": ""}, "correct": "A"}, {"title": "", "name": "", "article": "", "question": "54. How many integers between, but not including, 20 and 30 have a prime factorization with exactly 3 factors that are NOT necessarily unique? (Note: 1 is NOT a prime number.)", "choices": {"A": "1", "B": "2", "C": "3", "D": "4", "E": "5"}, "correct": "B"}, {"title": "", "name": "", "article": "", "question": "55. The graph of , , and   are shown in the standard (x,y) coordinate plane below. The shaded region is the solution set to one of the following systems of inequalities. Which system is it?", "choices": {"A": "", "B": "", "C": " ", "D": "", "E": ""}, "correct": "A"}, {"title": "", "name": "", "article": "", "question": "56. The function f(x) is shown below with several points labeled. Another function, g(x), is defined such that  What is g(4) ?", "choices": {"A": "-4", "B": "-1", "C": "1", "D": "4", "E": "7"}, "correct": "D"}, {"title": "", "name": "", "article": "", "question": "57. The ratio of a to b is 6 to 1, and the ratio of b to c is 12 to 1. What is the value of  ?", "choices": {"A": "", "B": "", "C": "", "D": "", "E": ""}, "correct": "D"}, {"title": "", "name": "", "article": "", "question": "58. The frequency histogram below shows the distribution of the heights, in inches, of 11 basketball players.Using the data from the frequency histogram, what is the sum of the mean and the median of this distribution?", "choices": {"A": "141", "B": "142", "C": "143", "D": "144", "E": "145"}, "correct": "A"}, {"title": "", "name": "", "article": "", "question": "59. In the standard (x,y) coordinate plane, what is the y-intercept of the graph of the function defined below?", "choices": {"A": "-5", "B": "-3", "C": "-1", "D": "2.5", "E": "3"}, "correct": "A"}, {"title": "", "name": "", "article": "", "question": "60. What is the matrix product   \uff1f", "choices": {"A": "", "B": "", "C": "", "D": "", "E": ""}, "correct": "E"}]}